Guide to the Francis C. Moon papers, 1961-2009.
Moon, Francis C. papers
- Series II. Publications
  - "Comments on 'Survey of Reactor Aspects of Compact Fusion Concepts'", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Elastic Conducting Structures in Pulsed Magnetic Fields", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Earnshaw's Theorem and Magnetoelastic Buckling of Superconducting Structures", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "The Fractal Dimension of the Two-Well Potential Strange Attractor", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Fractal Boundary for Chaos in a Two-State Mechanical Oscillator", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Parametric Stiffness Control of Flexible Structures", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Stability Analysis of a Robotic Mechanism Using Computer Algebra", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Pre- and Post-Processing for Stream-Fuction Eddy Current Calculations", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Double Poincare Sections of a Quasi-Periodically Forced, Chaotic Attractor", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Teaching Engineering Analysis Using Symbolic Algebra and Calculus", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Fractal Basin Boundaries and Homoclinic Orbits for Periodic Motion in a Two-Well Potential", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Dynamic Stresses ina Buried Cylinder Due to Ground Shock", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "New Research Directions for Chaotic Phenomena in Solid Mechanics", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Nonlinear Dynamic Systems", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Structural Dynamics", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Mechanics of Electronic and Electromechanical Devices", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "An Optical Technique for Measuring Fractal Dimensions of Planar Poincare Maps", 1986 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Fractals and Chaos in Mechanical Systems", 1986 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Stability and Vibration of Internal Windings of Superconducting Solenoid Magnets", 1986 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Chaotic Dynamics in Magnetic and Magneto-Mechanical Systems", 1986 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Fractals and Chaos: New Concepts in Mechanics", 1986 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Fractals in Physics", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Chaotic Dynamics in Solid Mechanics", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Evidence for Homoclinic Orbits as a Precursor to Chaos in a Magnetic Pendulum", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Nonlinear Dynamics", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "High Tc Superconducting Magnetic Bearings for Levitation of High Speed Rotors", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Hysteric Levitation Forces in Superconducting Ceramics", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Chaotic Motion of an Elastic-Plastic Beam", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Experiments in Chaotic Dynamics", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Superconductivity and Mechanical Engineering", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Flexural Stiffness and Modulus of Elasticity of Flower Stalks from Allium Sativum as Measured by Multiple Resonance Frequency Spectra", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Superconductivity: As Temperatures Rise, So Do Demands on MEs", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Nonlinear and Chaotic Fluidelastic Vibrations of a Flexible Pipe Conveying Fluid", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Fractals and Chaos in Mechanical Systems", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Chaotic Vibrations of a Magnet Near a Superconductor", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Dynamic Magnetic Forces in Superconducting Ceramics", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "A Renaissance in Mechanical Engineering", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Laminated Piezopolymer Plates for Torsion and Bending Sensors and Actuators", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Chaotic Oscillations of the Autonomous System of a Constrained Pipe Conveying Field", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Autocorrelation on Symbol Dynamics for a Chaotic Dry-Friction Oscillator", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Resonance in a High-Speed Flexible-Arm Robot", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Chaotic Oscillations of a High Speed Flexible-Arm Robot", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Coming to Terms With Chaos", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "The Power of Magnetic Levitation", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Modal Sensors/Actuators", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Criteria for Chaos of a Three-Well Potential Oscillator with Homoclinic and Heteroclinic Orbits", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Experimental Study of Chaotic Vibrations in a Pin-Jointed Space Truss Structure", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Fractal Basin Boundaries in a Two-Degree-of-Freedom Nonlinear System", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Bifurcations and Chaos ina Forced Zero-Stiffness Impact Oscillator", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Spacial and Temporal Chaos in Elastic Continua", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Spatio-Temporal Chaos in a Vibrating String with Nonlinear Amplitude Constraints", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "High-speed Rotation of Magnets on High Tc Superconducting Bearings", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Levitation Forces, Relaxation and Magnetic Stiffness of Melt-Quenched YBa2Cu3Ox", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Levitation Force and Magnetic Stiffness in Bulk High-Temperature Superconductors", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Magnetic Forces in High-Tc Superconducting Bearings", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Materials Research Issues in Superconducting Levitation and Suspension as Applied to Magnetic Bearings", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Symbol Dynamic Maps of Spatial-Temporal Chaotic Vibrations in a String of Impact Oscillators", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Experiments on Co-Located Feedback Vibration Suppression in a Space Frame Using New Magnetic Actuators", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Friction Measurements During Regular and Chaotic Oscillations: Paper on Paper and Titanium on Titanium", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Experimental Evidence for Chaotic Response in a Feedback System", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Experimental Measurement of Chaotic Attractors in Solid Mechanics", 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Chaotic Sources of Noise in Machine Acoustics", 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Raised to a Higher Plane", 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Levitation Studies in High Tc Superconductors at Lower Temperatures and High Fields", 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Piezoelectric Modal Sensor/Actuator Pairs for Critical Active Damping Vibration Control", 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "3-D Spatial Chaos in the Elastica and the Spinning Top: Kirchhoff Analogy", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Coming to Grips with Chaos", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Chaotic Flow-Induced Vibration of a Flexible Tube with End Mass", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Free Vibrations of a Thin Elastica by Normal Modes", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Limit Cycles in an Elasto-Plastic Oscillator", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Superconducting Bearings for High Load Applications", 1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Bifurcation Sequences of a Coulomb Friction Oscillator", 1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Non-Trivial Dynamics in a Driven String with Impact Non-Linearity", 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Amplitude-Dependent Magnetic Stiffness of Melt-Quenched YBa2Cu3O7-δ Superconductors", 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Chaotic Dynamics and Fractals in Material Removal Processes", 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Measures of Robust Dynamical Behavior and Fractal Basin Boundaries for Two- and Three-Well Potential Problems", 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "A Dynamical Model for a High-Tc Superconductor and Magnet System", 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Transition from Soliton to Chaotic Motion During Impact of a Nonlinear Elastic Structure", 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Dynamic Behavior of a Bilinear Hysteretic Elasto-Plastic Oscillator, Part I: Free Oscillations", 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Dynamic Behavior of a Bilinear Hysteretic Elasto-Plastic Oscillator, Part II: Oscillations Under Periodic Impulse Forcing", 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Chaotic Levitated Motion of a Magnet Supported by Superconductor", 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Chaos in a Forced Dry-Friction Oscillator: Experiments and Numerical Modelling", 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Chaotic Scattering of Waves from Nonlinear Scatterers", 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Transition from Soliton to Chaotic Motion Following Sudden Excitation of a Nonlinear Structure", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Levitation Forces, Stiffness and Force-Creep in YBCO High-Tc Superconducting Thin Films", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Chaotic Mixing in Rigid, Perfectly Plastic Material", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Chaotic Non-Planar Vibrations of the Thin Elastica, Part I: Experimental Observation of Planar Instability", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Chaotic Non-Planar Vibrations of the Thin Elastica, Part II: Derivation and Analysis of a Low-Dimensional Model", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Multifractals in Elastic Tube Vibrations Due to Internal Flow", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Experimental Dynamics of a Hanging Cable Carrying Two Concentrated Masses", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Levitation Drift of a Magnet Supported by a High-Tc Superconductor Under Vibration", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Capacitance Based Tunable Micromechanical Resonators", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Development of a Parallel Link Crane: Modeling and Control of a System with Unilateral Cable Constraints", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Robust Control of a Shape-Changing Flexible Robot Arm", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Differential Laser Interferometer for Nanometer Displacement Measurements", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Enhanced Noncollocated Control of a Shape-Changing Flexible Robot Arm", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Controlling Chaos in a Two-Well Oscillator", 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "An Experimental Spatio-Temporal State Transition of Coupled Magneto-Elastic System", 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Bifurcation and Multifractal Vibration in Dynamics of a High-Tc Superconducting Levitation System", 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Solitons, Chaos and Modal Interactions in Periodic Structures", 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Helical Wave Oscillators in a Row of Cylinders in a Cross-Flow", 1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Future Applications of Superconducting Bearings", 1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Dynamics and Chaos in Manufacturing Processes", 1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Chaotic Systems and Manufacturing", 1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Experimental Characterization of Quasiperiodicity and Chaos in a Mechanical System With Delay", 1999 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Dynamical Friction Behavior in a Forced Oscillator with a Compliant Contact", 1999 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Dynamical Behavior of Flywheel Rotor Suspended by Hysteric Force of HTSC Magnetic Bearing", 1999 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Bifurcation and Hunting Phenomena of Rotating Speed in a Flexible Rotor System Caused by Whirling Motion", 1999 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Quenching Stick-Slip Chaos With Dither", 2000 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Reflections on Nonlinear Dynamics of Machines and Structures", 2000 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Nonlinear Models for Complex Dynamics in Cutting Materials", 2001 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Spatio-Temporal Dynamics in Large Arrays of Fluid-Elastic, Toda-Type Oscillators", 2001 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Nonlinear Techniques to Characterize Prechatter and Chatter Vibrations in the Machining of Metals", 2001 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Subcritical Hopf Bifurcation in the Delay Equation Model for Machine Tool Vibrations", 2001 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Local Complexity and Global Nonlinear Modes in Large Arrays of Fluid-Elastic Oscillators", 2002 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Robert Willis and Franz Reuleaux: Pioneers in the Theory of Machines", 2003 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Franz Reuleaux: Contributions to 19th Century Kinematics and Theory of Machines", 2003 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Experiments in Control and Anti-Control of Chaos in a Dry Friction Oscillator", 2003 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Nonlinear System Identification of Multi-Degree-of-Freedom Systems", 2003 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Mode-Coupled Regenerative machine Tool Vibrations", 2004 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Nonlinear System Identification of Systems with Periodic Limit-Cycle Response", 2005 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "3D-Printing the History of Mechanisms", 2005 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Coexisting Chaotic and Periodic Dynamics in Clock Escapements", 2006 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Elastic Waves and Solid Armature Contact Pressure in Electromagnetic Launchers", 2006 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Empirical Dry-Friction Modeling in a Forced Oscillator Using Chaos", 2007 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Experimental Reconsideration of Spatio-Temporal Dynamics Observed in Fluid-Elastic Oscillator Arrays from Complex System Viewpoint: From Vibrating Pipes in Heat Exchangers to Waving Plants in Agricultural Fields", 2007 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "A History of Dynamics of Machines and Mechanisms from Leonardo to Timoshenko", 2007 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Series III. Patents
  - Superconducting Rotating Assembly, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Author: Moon, F.C., Raj, R.
  - Superconducting Rotating Assembly, Folder 2, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Superconducting Rotating Assembly, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Piezoelectric Polymer Laminates for Torsional and Bending Modal Control, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Author: Lee, C.K., Moon, F.C.
  - Magnetic Flexure System for Determining Superconductive Properties of a Sample, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Author: Moon, F.C.
  - Superconducting Levitating Bearing, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Superconducting Bearing Correspondence and Miscellaneous Patent Correspondence, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - All Superconducting Rotor-Bearing System, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Series IV. Photographs and Slides
  - Kinetic Sculpture Course (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Author: F. Moon
  - Three-Well Potential Chaos- Basin Boundaries (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Author: F. Moon, G.-X. Li
  - Two-Well Potential Chaos: Basin Boundaries (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Four-Well Potential Chaos: Basin Boundaries (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 'Elastica' Flexible Robot Arm (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Magnetic Levitation (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Misc. Photographs (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Chaos Art Show- NY 1990, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - IUTAM Symposium on Chaos, Cornell Univ. Photo, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Negatives of F. Moon's Japanese Mag-lev Transportation Photos, early 1980's, 1980's (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Plasticity Chaos Fractal Photos, Negatives of Chaotic Fractal Photos (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - High Currents Around Cracks in Metals photographs, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1st Poincare Maps of Chaotic Vibrations in Mechanical Systems, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Dynamic Stability of Model of Mag-Lev Vehicle on Rotating Circular Track, 1973-78 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Stability of Multi Superconducting Magnets of Magnetic Fusion Reactors, 1976-82 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Photos of Cornell 'Elasticarm', 1990 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Photos of High Current Arc Striking a Flexible Beam, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Photos of 16 Coil Superconducting Magnet Torus Model for Magnetic Fusion…, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Space Truss Structures Dynamics, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Infrared Photos of Eddy Currents in Thin Plates for Mag-lev Applications, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Superconducting Levitation Photos, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Chladni Vibration Patterns, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Rotating Pendulum Chaos: Basin Boundaries (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Mag-lev Dynamics: Cornell, 1975-82 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Bone Mechanics- Torsional Modulus, 1970-75 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Infrared Photos of Eddy Currents and Thin Plates, 1970-80 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Butterfly Chaos' Four-well Potential, Basin Boundaries, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Poincare Maps- Two Well Potential, 1975-80 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Chaos- Basin Boundary Fractals, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Dipole Magnet Stability (Magnets on ping-pong balls in water-circular mag…), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Experimental Poincare Maps 2-well Potential 0-180 degree Strange Attractor, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - 1st Poincare Maps of Chaotic Vibrations in Mechanical Systems, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Series V. Videos
  - Master MAG-LEV (Misc. Old Filmd. Chaos, Levitations, Stability (Fusion), V-7048 (Box 4)
    Creator: W. Holmes
  - The Strange New Science of Chaos, March 3, 1989; V-7049 (Box 4)
    Creator: NOVA
  - MAG-LEV Cornell, V-7050 (Box 4)
    Creator: Cornell
  - Elastic Arm Robot, Base Motor Oscillation (Bending Vibration), September 1994; V-7051 (Box 4)
    Creator: E. Catto
  - 2nd Copy: Elastic Arm Robot, Base Motor Oscillation (Bending Vibration), V-7052 (Box 4)
  - Space Structures, Elastic Arm, V-7053 (Box 4)
    Creator: F. C. Moon
    15 Min
  - Reuleaux Models, Cornell, 2001; V-7054 (Box 4)
  - Strogatz Chaos Demos, V-7055 (Box 4)
    Creator: Steve Strogatz
    45 Min
  - MAG-LEV in Japan, V-7056 (Box 4)
    "Levitated Transportation" label also on jacket
  - MAG-LEV Cornell-Japan, etc., V-7057 (Box 4)
    Note on jacket: "Copy on DVD 1/08".
  - Encounters: Impressions of Transrapid Travel, V-7058 (Box 4)
    Note on Jacket: "German MAG-LEV"
  - German MAG-LEV Promo Video, ca. 1995; V-7059 (Box 4)
  - The Future's so Bright (Sr. Class Video), 2001; V-7060 (Box 4)
    Creator: MechE Senior Class 2001
    A DVD copy of this is kept in the MAE undergrad office.
  - Levitated Transportation, V-7061 (Box 4)
    13 Min
  - Repulsion Test YBa2Cu3Ox7, V-7062 (Box 4)
  - Summary Video of F.I.V. Flow Visualization, October 1993; V-7063 (Box 4)
    Creator: George Muntean
  - Solution of a DDE in a 3-D Space, August 26, 1995; V-7064 (Box 4)
    Creator: Mark Johnson
    Includes: 1. Radial Sections Through "Attractor" (audio is x(+)). 2. Trajectory Evolution (no audio)
  - Elasticarm, December 2000; V-7065 (Box 4)
    Creator: Rebecca Ringe
  - Introduction to the Chaos Water Wheel, V-7066 (Box 4)
    Creator: Kriebel and Holsapple, Inc.
  - Two-Well, V-7067 (Box 4)
    8 Min
  - Basin of Attraction in a Driven Dynamical System, V-7068 (Box 4)
    Creator: Terry Bump & J.P. Cusumano
    Other label on jacket: "Cornell National Supercomputer Facility-Animation Video"
  - Levitron-Demo, V-7069 (Box 4)
    Creator: Richard Rand
  - USA-Japan System 1. Title Illegible 2. Chaos-Wapportel, 1973, 1988; V-7070 (Box 4)
    Other label on cassette: "Impact Dynamics, Origin Unknown?"
  - Part I: Vibration of SC. Under Levitating Magnet. Large Ring with Turbine., ca. 1990; V-7071 (Box 4)
  - HSST MAG-LEV Japan: 1. HSST-The Transportation System We've Been Watiting For. 2. HSST-Largest Attraction at '88 SAITAMA EXPO, December 1986, July 1988; V-7072 (Box 4)
    1. 13 Min 2. 10:20 Min
  - Magnetic Pendulum Chaos, December 1992; V-7073 (Box 4)
  - Animated Basin Boundaries (raw footage), V-7074 (Box 4)
  - Basin Boundaries: Parametric Pendulum with Spring, V-7075 (Box 4)
    Creator: J. Cusumano (Penn State)
    Other Label on Jacket: "Global Sensitivity Analysis of a Nonlinear System using Animated Basin Boundaries."
  - Chaos and Fractals in Simple Physical Systems as Revealed by the Computer, V-7076 (Box 4)
    Creator: Frank Varosi & James A. Yorke
  - Kinetic Sculpture Course Videos
    - Kinetic Sculpture Projects, April, 1996; V-7080 (Box 4)
    - Kinetic Sculpture Project #1, 1999; V-7081 (Box 4)
    - Kinetic Sculpture Projects, 1999; V-7082 (Box 4)
    - Kinetic Sculpture Project #1, 2000; V-7083 (Box 4)
    - Kinetic Sculpture Show, Cornell, Spring 2000; V-7084 (Box 4)
    - Kinetic Sculpture Project #1, Spring 2001; V-7085 (Box 4)
    - Kinetic Sculpture Project #2, Spring 2001; V-7086 (Box 4)
    - Kinetic Sculpture Show, Cornell, May 1, 2001; V-7087 (Box 4)
    - Kinetic Sculpture 2 Projects, Spring 2002; V-7088 (Box 4)
    - Kinetic Sculpture Projects, V-7089 (Box 4)
    - "Tops" 7 min/Machines by Ganson 60 min, V-7090 (Box 4)
- Series VI. Drawings for Publications
  - Chaos Book Figures and First Draft, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Diagrams, Graphs, and Illustrations prepped for publication
  - Chaotic Vibrations-Good Figures, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Figures-Chaos Book, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Moon, Wiley-Chaotic Vibrations (1-50), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Moon, Wiley-Chaotic Vibrations (51-100), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Moon, Wiley-Chaotic Vibrations (101-150), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Moon, Wiley-Chaotic Vibrations (151-200), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Chaotic and Fractal Dynamics, Wiley and F.C. Moon, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chaotic and Fractal Dynamics, Wiley and F.C. Moon (2), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Kinetic Sculpture Course, 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Photographs
  - Superconducting Levitation, Wiley and F.C. Moon, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Includes Diagrams, Graphs, and Photographs prepped for publication
- Series VI. Director of Sibley School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering and Chair of the Department of Theoretical and Applied Mechanics Documents
  - Faculty Senate Committee--Faculty Salaries, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Sibley School (MAE) Long Range Development Plan, c.1990 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Pratt Institute Blue Ribbon Panel, September 4-6, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Dean Memos, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Dean Memos, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Dean Memos, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Dean Memos, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Dean Memos, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Dean Memos, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Report to Dean, August, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Dean Memos (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Dean and Sibley School, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Director Search, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Long Range Development Plan, 1990-1995 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Moon Lab Space/Theoretical and Applied Mechanics, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Professor Geoffrey Ludford, Theoretical and Applied Mechanics, Obituary, Library Books, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Director Search, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Sibley Review, Moon Lab, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering-Sibley School-Five Year Summary, Miscellaneous Memos, 1987-1992 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - SUPERMAG Associates, NASA - OAST, January 18, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - F.C. Moon Mechancial and Aerospace Engineering Curriculum Proposal, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Theoretical and Applied Mechanics - F.C. Moon Chair, 1980-1987 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Includes: "Kimball Space/Joe Burns" (1988), "TAM Annual Report and Miscellaneous" (August 1987), "New Graduate Students" (1986-1987), "P.P. Bijlaard's Papers".
  - Ranking of Graduate Programs, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Dean Memos-Theoretical and Applied Mechanics, Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, Annual Report, 1986-1989 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - F.C. Moon Sibley School (Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering) Director's Log, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    Contained in Binder
- Series VIII. 16mm Films
  - Torus in Dewar (Buckling), F-1017 (Box 6)
    Creator: FC Moon
    Location: Cornell University
    Original B&W Pos Low Contrast
  - No Name, November 1978; F-1018 (Box 6)
    Location:
    Infrared
  - Discrete track wheel, stable, Flutter, Also "V" track chaos clip, F-1019 (Box 6)
  - Mag-Lev Dynamics, Rotating Wheel, "L" track stable dynamics, June 1990; F-1020 (Box 6)
  - Original Mag Lev JL Flat Plate, F-1021 (Box 6)
  - Active Structural Control Activity, F-1022 (Box 6)
    Creator: FC Moon/E. Dowell
    Location: Princeton University
  - Buckling of SC Magnets in a Torus, F-1023 (Box 6)
    Orig. B&W Neg.
  - Active Structural Control Activity, F-1024 (Box 6)
  - 16 Coil Torus, F-1025 (Box 6)
    Color Negative
  - Chaos Demo, F-1026 (Box 6)
    Creator: J. Crutchfield
    Location: Berkeley, California
  - Flutter, Div., Chaos, F-1027 (Box 6)
    Location: Cornell
    "V" Track
  - MIT Magna-Plane, c. 1977-1978; F-1028 (Box 6)
    Location: MIT
  - Mag Lev. Reel # 1, August 1972; F-1029 (Box 6)
  - 16 Coil Torus, Buckling, 1977; F-1030 (Box 6)
    Extra Footage
  - Mag-Lev Stanford R.J. Vehicle, F-1031 (Box 6)
  - Mag-Lev Effect of Mass on Dynamics, F-1032 (Box 6)